快跑  快跑
Run, run is all that.
我已经犯心脏病了
I already have a heart attack.
别想逃  小子
Don't wanna go, buddy.
没搞错吧 我们追的是人吗
What the hell was that? What we're chasing?
你去那边
Go that way!
别动
Don't move!
别想逃 投降吧
Don't want go! Give it up!
这边 快快
Come this way! Come on, Let's go! Let's go!
天呐  他要爬到屋顶去了
Oh, god. He's going to the roof.
快快
Come on, go!
妈的
Damn it!
快  快
Go, go!
不  唐尼  不要 太远了
No, Donny, no. It's too far.
我可以在家休养
I can rest at home.
两天内你就别想离开了
We can't release you for at least two days.
你断了两根骨头  严重的脑震荡
You have two broken bones, a severe concussion,
肺也受了伤
Collapsed lung.
但死不了人  对吗
But you didn't find anything life-threatening, right?
你从30英尺高摔下来  你差点就死了
You fell 30 feet. You should have died.
这才是重点 你能闭嘴吗
I think that was the point. Could you shut up?
你是想自杀
You have suicidal thoughts?
想都没想过  完全没有
Not once. Never.
他不想自杀
He doesn't want to kill himself.
他只是觉得自己快死了
He just thinks he's gonna die soon,
所以就无所谓了  现在你闭嘴
So it doesn't really matter, now you shut up.
你每次出状况
I'm the one you're not covering
可都是我担着
When you pull your crazy stunts.
你为什么觉得自己快死了
Why do you think you're gonna die soon?
我父亲  祖父  曾祖父
Well, my dad, grandfather, and great-grandfather
都在40岁时
All dropped dead of heart problems
因心脏问题猝死
Right after they turned 40.
某人下周就满40了
Look who turns 40 next week.
我可以给你推荐一位心脏科权威  如果你 都去过了
I can refer you to a cardiologist, if you-- Nah, I've been there,
所有人
All of them.
30出头时  我就不停地看医生
I spent my early 30s going from one doctor to another.
每个人都说我的心脏很健康
Every single one says my heart's fine.
-而你觉得他们错了  -我知道他们错了
- And you think they're wrong?  - I know they're wrong.
但我能怎么办
But what can I do?
话说回来  日子还得继续过
At a certain point, you just got to live your life.
说到过日子
By live your life,
你是指到处找死
You mean risk your life.
如果你真的生病了
If there is something wrong,
我知道有位医生能找出病因
I know a doctor who will find it.
靠  我过十分钟再来
Oh, god! I'll be back in ten.
我在撕肚脐上的汗毛
I'm picking lint out of my belly button.
少瞎扯了
This is ridiculous.
我要把书房改成卧室
I'm converting the study into a bedroom.
6周了
Six weeks.
比我预计的要长
Longer than I thought it would take...
我可是一直睡在你家客厅
For you to notice that I'm sleeping in your living room,
你也不给我找个好地方
And offer other options.
我没想到你会呆这么久
I didn't expect you to be here this long.
没错  但不是你继续容忍我的原因
True, but that's not why you didn't extend the invitation.
你真要深入分析这件事
Do you really need to deconstruct this?
你不想让我睡在你跟安波儿睡过的床
You didn't want me to sleep where you and Amber slept.
-是  没错  -她死后
- Okay, yes, you do.  - After she died,
你把书房改成卧室
You converted the study to a bedroom
把卧室变为书房
And the bedroom to a study...
但卧室终究不是书房  是圣殿
Except it's not a study, it's a shrine.
恕我直言
Can I tell you something?
我其实没在拔毛
I wasn't picking lint out of my belly button.
够了
Okay.
我还没准备好把话题
I am not ready to transition
从我去世女友的圣殿
From my dead girlfriend's shrine
转移到你的...晨练
To your... Morning glory.
之后会有床垫送来
I'll have a mattress delivered
装好后让你睡
And set up for you in the tabernacle.
只需每周二还我  我要杀生拜祭
I just need it tuesdays for animal sacrifices.
天啊
Oh, man!
这病人是颗拴在遗传链上的定时炸弹
Patient's a genetic time bomb.
没有导火索
There's no fuse.
就不是炸弹
He's not a bomb.
现在  他连病人都不是
Right now he's not a patient either.
你要我们无视他祖上三代的心脏病吗
You saying we ignore three generations of cardiac problems?
不是无视
I'm not ignoring it.
是巧合
I'm labeling it a coincidence.
你讨厌巧合
You hate coincidence.
我们达成一致了  这是一回事
We reconciled. It was a whole thing.
广袤大地
Big country.
一家三代都因非遗传性心脏病
It's statistically probable that someone
在40岁左右归西
Has three generations that died around age 40
统计理论上是有可能的
With nongenetic heart issues.
霉运可不长记性 基因长
Dice have no memory. Genes do.
如果每遇这种状况
If we ran a battery of tests
就进行一堆的检查...
On every nonsymptomatic statistical anomaly--
这人会在40岁会死掉  这个心里阴影
The guy goes every day
伴随着他每一天的生活
Assuming his life will end at age 40.
所以不结婚  不要孩子
Never got married, no kids,
因为他不想同他父亲一样 死在他们面前
Because he didn't want to die on them the same way his dad died on him.
你想接这个案子
You want to take this case
因为他不过是一只孤独可怜的小狗狗
'Cause he's yet another lonely, sad puppy.
你该去做兽医
You should have been a vet.
这案子有理有据
It's a legitimate case.
对心脏进行遗传性鉴别诊断
Differential diagnosis for genetic heart conditions.
你吃这套吗
That sold you?
马方综合症  布鲁加达综合症 还有你
Marfan syndrome, Brugada. And you?
高胆固醇血症
Emilio hypercholesterolemia.
他附和你
He's only agreeing with you
是因为想睡了你
'cause he wants to have sex with you.
顺带一提  我也很赞同你
And by the way, I agree with you too,
尤其是你的底裤
Especially in those pants.
我们绝对没有在浪费时间
We're not wasting our time.
上周  奇斯说我才是真正的头儿
And last week, Chase said that I was the de facto boss.
要真正的行医执照  医院才买账
Hospitals don't recognize de facto medical licenses.
从基因检测开始
Let's start with genetic tests.
做心电图  心导管检查
Get an EK, cardiac cath--
通过回波检查心脏完整性
And an echo to check the integrity of his heart.
我先检查血样
I'll start on blood samples.
我忘了戴表
I forgot my watch.
我发誓早上看见你戴了 一定是落在更衣室了
Could have sworn I saw you put it on this morning. Must be in the locker room.
一会儿就来
I'll be right back.
我想知道你的打算
I need to know what your plans are.
首先拿下柏林
First we take Berlin.
接着迂回偷袭波兰
And then we circle around behind Poland
然后欢呼  哦耶
And yell, "surprise!"
我指你的工作
With regards to your employment.
我喜欢事物展示本来面目
I like things the way they are.
我有谜可解 而且没有你来蔑视我
I get just enough puzzle to solve without the scornful visits from you...
现在却没了
Until now.
装模作样时间已经够长
Pretend time's been going on long enough.
我没有行医执照  只能装模作样
I don't have a medical license. All I can do is pretend.
那从明天起我也开始
And I'm gonna have payroll send you
付你装模作样的支票
Over some pretend checks starting tomorrow.
要想拿回执照  你还得巡房120小时
You need to complete 120 hours of rounds to re-qualify.
不  我不要
No, I don't.
不是说你搞不定我
I'm not saying you don't win.
只是你真要让我替你的白痴手下
I'm just saying do you really need to punish me
举一星期的笔记板  来惩罚我吗
By making me carry a clipboard for your lackey of the week?
这是政府规定
It's a state requirement.
我必须证明你确实完全符合...
I have to certify that you've completed all your require--
完全正确
Exactly.
规定指定你必须做什么
The requirement sets out what you have to do--
证明嘛 你一只手也能做到
Certify, Which you can do with one hand tied behind your back.
现在  如果你想绑住我的双手
Now, if you want to tie my hands...
周四辛格医生负责监督巡房
Dr. Singh supervises rounds on thursdays,
7点开始
Starts at 7:00.
没有发现
Nothing.
那现在呢
So what now?
送他回家
Send him home.
让他继续相信自己会猝死
To continue believing he's gonna drop dead?
等他到七老八十  就会相信我们了
When he turns 70, he'll believe us.
还有别的没查
There are other things we can check.
曾祖父的骨架保存完好
Skeleton of great-grandfather's in decent shape.
祖父的遗传物质也还在
Subsurface genetic material from grandpa's fine,
老爸就彻底的灰飞烟灭了
Leaving one bowl of purified dad.
老爸归你
You do the dad.
我打赌他的棺材密封很好
I take it he had a sealed casket.
手表的事是你瞎掰的吧
The watch story was crap, right?
我忘了
I forgot it.
没什么大不了
It's no big deal.
你想躲开 迪巴拉去世的那间重症监护室
You were avoiding the ICU where Dibala died.
我给心脏钠离子通道做个基因排序
I'll sequence the gene for the cardiac sodium channel.
我当时觉得我快要惊恐了
I felt like I was gonna have a panic attack.
我已经跨过了这道坎...
I've crossed some line...
但却不知道如何回到原点
And I'm having trouble getting back to the other side.
我可以给病人转移病房
I can move the patient to another room.
卡梅隆会问的
Cameron will ask questions.
你应该告诉她
You should tell her.
她是你老婆
She's your wife.
你们怎么这么快就拿到了掘坟的法庭许可
How'd you get a court order to dig them up so fast?
只要他同意就可以了
We just needed the guy's consent.
-找到什么线索吗  -还没
- You find anything?  - Not yet.
不过你正好赶上给爸爸做检查
But you're just in time to do the dad.
豪斯医生在吗
Doctor House?
他明早会回来
He'll be back in the morning.
我在报纸上看到 你正在医治一名警官
I read in the paper you're treating a police officer.
-唐尼·康普森  -在二楼
- Donny Compson?  - Second floor.
护士会帮您找到他的
A nurse will help you find him.
我不想见他
I don't want to see him.
唐尼和我早就分手了
Donny and I used to go out a long time ago.
他不想见我  我也不想见他
He doesn't want to see me. I don't want to see him.
那么  你是找我来寻求感情建议吗
So did you come to see me for personal advice?
你们在寻找导致他父亲和祖父
You're looking for genetic conditions, which makes sense,
发病的控制基因  这很有意义
With what happened to his dad and grandpa.
除非你是他的女友  兼妹妹
Unless you were his girlfriend and his sister,
否则不必担心
You got nothing to worry about.
我不是担心我自己
I'm not worried about me.
唐尼还不知道
Donny doesn't know this,
他有个儿子
But he has a son.
拨打分机号742
Dial extension 742.
告诉福曼医生  你有猛料要爆
Tell Dr. Foreman you got some cool information.
晚安
Good night.
你还好吗
You okay?
没事
Yeah, fine.
在唐尼祖父辈的15个基因片段
Couldn't find any consistent genetic mutations
找不到任何相似的基因突变
Across 15 areas between Donny's ancestors,
很可能标明本来就没有
Possibly indicating there isn't one.
但儿子给了我们一个新的数据接入点
But the son gives us a new data point.
一个未降解的DNA
And undegraded DNA.
我觉得他不想要孩子
I thought he didn't want kids.
-他没想  -豪斯在哪
- He didn't.  - Where's house?
亲爱的多愁善感的宝贝儿们
"Dear bleeding hearts,
介于此位病人的传奇故事不过是个巧合
"Since your patient's med history is a coincidence,
而且他并没有
"And he isn't...
得病
"Sick,
所以我先回学校了
"I've gone back to school.
120小时后见
Back in 120 hours."
牛人  我去取个血样
Charming. I'll get a blood sample.
如果我们要找到类似基因突变的细节
If we're looking for something as subtle as a mutation,
那么提取最纯的DNA就很重要
It makes sense to get the DNA where it's most pure.
难道要请他母亲同意  给他来个骨髓活检
You're gonna ask the mom to consent to a bone marrow biopsy?
如果她想一探唐尼的究竟
She wants to know if there's something wrong with Donny
那么最好听我们的
Just as badly as we do.
没错
Right.
因为祖父的病而穿刺10岁小孩的屁股
Spike a ten-year-old's hip because grandpa was sick.
如果她是对的...
If she's right...
我们就能救两个人了
We save two people.
我不愿意
I don't want to.
我们能出去谈谈吗
Can we speak outside for a moment?
好的
Yeah.
你应该告诉他
You need to tell him.
不行
I can't.
他的父亲从两栋楼之间
His father is down that hallway
跳了下来
Through those double doors.
我一直没有告诉过他真相
I've been lying to him his whole life.
他会怎么想我
What's he gonna think of me?
你在努力保护他
You're trying to protect him.
唐尼从不想要孩子
Donny never wanted kids.
他当然也不想见他
He certainly doesn't want to meet him.
如果唐尼死了  这是
If donny does die, this could be
麦克见他的唯一机会
Michael's only chance to meet his father.
经过免疫球蛋白治疗
After administration of immunoglobulin,
病人已再无疼痛现象 而且隔夜肺功能检测显示正常
Patient had no further pain, And overnight liver function tests are now normal.
病人可以出院了
Patient's ready to be released.
数据在下降
Stats are dropping.
-辛格医生  -她窒息了
- Doctor singh?  - She's choking.
-用你的手指  -她不能呼吸
- On your fingers. - She can't breathe.
豪斯
House...
请把你的手指从检测按钮上拿开
Please take your finger off the test button.
明白了  非常抱歉
I see. Wow, sorry about that.
我差点切开她的喉管
I could've slit her throat.
我们都是来学习的
Well, we're all here to learn.
你知道  卡迪医生警告我要注意你
You know, Dr. Cuddy warned me about you.
她没告诉你怎么阻止我吗
She tell you how to stop me?
我正在请您像个成年人一样  请住手
Look, I'm asking you as an adult to please stop.
这显然不是她的作风
Well, that obviously didn't come from her.
但也管用
But fair enough.
报告很出色  诺娜
Excellent presentation, Nona.
我搞砸了
Now I've done it.
尿流的到处都是
There's urine everywhere!
糟糕  师生关系中 最伟大的地方就是老师
Gosh. The great thing about the teacher-student relationship is the teacher
通常从学生那里学到更多东西
Can often learn more from the student.
你们学到什么了吗
Have you learned anything yet?
你有个儿子
You have a son.
我们分手时  我怀孕了
I was pregnant when we broke up.
很抱歉从没告诉过你
I'm sorry I never told you,
但我知道你不想要孩子
But I knew how you felt about having kids.
你没有权利
You had no right.
可能吧
Maybe.
但有点晚了
It's a little late for that.
他就在这
He's here.
他想见见你
He wants to meet you.
我不想见他
I don't want to meet him.
我从没向你要过一分钱
I've never asked you for a dime.
他来是为了帮助找到 你心脏的毛病
He's here to help find whatever's wrong with your heart.
又不是我请他来的
I didn't ask him.
我不想见他
I didn't want him.
只是和他打个招呼而已
Just say hi to him.
你好
Hi.
我是迈克尔
I'm Michael.
你好
Hi.
我是你的...
I'm your-- Uh...
是的  你妈妈告诉我了
Yeah, your mother told me.
等你好些后
When you get better,
我们可以一起做些什么
Maybe we could do something.
比如看电影
See a movie?
不
No.
我爸爸在我像你这么大的时候死了
My dad died when I was your age.
是我这一生最痛苦的事情
It was the most painful thing I ever went through.
相信我吧  因为我知道这有多么痛苦
Trust me, as much as I'm sure this hurts right now,
为了他好
It's better.
请带他离开这 走吧
Please take him out of here. Come on.
28根心血管的染色体
Chromosomes for 28 cardiovascular conditions
结构都正常有序
Are normally numbered in structure.
没有转移  缺失或者反转
No translocations, deletions, or inversions.
我没注意到那孩子他老爸的染色体
I didn't notice that the kid's d-a-d-d-y chromosome
因他人多愁善感的染色体而有严重的损毁
Has been severely damaged by someone else's bleeding heart chromosome.
让迈克尔做骨髓活检是唯一的方法
It was the only way to get Michael to do the marrow biopsy.
我坚信有不少的谎言穿插其中
I'm sure there are plenty of lies would've worked just as well,
除了多年的求诊治疗
Except without the years of therapy.
-你不用上课吗  -休假
- Don't you have school?  - Recess.
那么留给我们的是什么
So where does that leave us?
奇斯
Chase?
抱歉  你说什么
Sorry. What?
我是说  你觉得这鞋的 颜色好看吗
I was saying, "do you think these shoes work in this color?"
让他回家吧
Send him home.
他不相信自己是健康的
He's not gonna believe he's healthy.
你不擅长自己的工作
You're not very good at your job.
-你不配得到糖果奖励  -他一辈子
- You don't deserve candy.  - He's been preparing
都在准备死于40岁
His whole life to die at age 40.
有无数的医生 告诉过他  他没事
He's had dozens of doctors tell him he's fine.
你觉得你会改变他的想法吗
You think you can change his thinking?
是的  我可以  奇斯  来
Yeah, I do. Chase, walk with me.
刚才你可是贡献不小啊
Great contributions back there.
没什么情况  我也无话可说
There's no case. I had nothing to add.
无话可说
You had nothing to add...
因为你心不在焉
Because you were distracted.
一个小魔鬼在你的肩膀上
A little devil on your shoulder
说你杀了人 而现在小天使也不甘示弱
Told you to kill a guy, And now the little angel won't shut up,
告诉你你将涅槃于水深火热之中
Telling you you're gonna burn in a lake of fire.
我没事
I'm fine.
你不该没事
You shouldn't be.
找人聊聊
Talk to someone.
文献要在7周内完成
Docs fixed me up in seven weeks.
这10分钟  你是最好的
You're... Ten minutes, tops.
谢谢
Thanks.
很高兴咱们有这样的时刻
Glad we had this little moment.
跟我来
Come on.
我是豪斯医生
I'm Dr. House.
你什么也没发现  是吗
You couldn't find anything, could you?
你有奥尔托利综合症
You have Ortoli syndrome.
奇斯医生
Dr. Chase?
-你确定吗  -化验室不骗人的
- You sure?  - Tests don't lie.
是的
Right.
那是
Well, it's--it's a...
一种很罕见的病例 肾上腺激素停止分泌
It's a very rare disorder that short-circuits the adrenals,
引发心脏停搏
Which short-circuits the heart.
等等等等  谁会在意
Blah, blah, blah, blah. Who cares
这些拗口的医学名词
About medical mumbo jumbo?
告诉他治疗方案
Tell him the treatment.
很复杂
It's... Well, it's--it's complicated.
医生总是喜欢 故弄玄虚
Doctors always want to make everything sound so complicated.
[豪斯自创]
It's nabsent
-什么  -[豪斯自创]
- What?  - Nabsent
是的
Yes.
所以我们现在要做的就是写个药方
So all we have to do now is write a prescription
让他吃药
And, uh, have him pick up the pills.
什么  就这样吗
What? That's it?
吃点药我就好了
I take some pills, and I'm gonna be okay?
真正的悲剧是如果提布伦祛病技术
The real tragedy here is that the Tiburon swab technology
在你爸爸那个年代就发明了的话
Didn't exist to detect Ortoli back in your dad's day.
他可能还活着
He could've lived.
谢谢
Thank you.
签了这份出院证明
If you'll sign these discharge papers,
我给你一瓶药
I'll get you a bottle of meds.
一天两片  吃一个星期
Take one twice a day for a week,
你就会健康长寿了
You'll live a long, healthy life.
去开门  豪斯
Answer the door, House.
一定是找你的
It's got to be for you.
你在看电视吗
Are you watching TV?
是门在响
It's the door!
-你刚才打电话了吗  -没有
- Were you on the phone?  - No.
-刚才你在说话吗  -没有  只有我自己
- Just now, were you talking?  - No. I'm alone.
你没事吧  豪斯
You okay, House?
你来干什么
Why are you here?
唐尼出院后四小时身体崩溃了
Donny collapsed four hours after we discharged him.
他死了
He's dead.
公寓管理员在洗衣间的地板上发现了他
His apartment manager found him on the floor in the laundry room.
说他当时停止呼吸
Said he wasn't breathing.
他打了急救电话  但是太迟了
He called the EMTs, but it was too late.
是我用薄荷糖送他回的家
I sent the guy home with mints.
不管是什么病  我们都遗漏了
Whatever it is, we all missed it.
我忽略了事情有遗漏的事实
I missed the fact that there was something to miss.
我这是怎么了
What is wrong with me?
你有很好的理由
You had good reason.
病人没有表现出症状
Patient presented with no symptoms,
他的化验都是阴性的
And all his tests came back negative.
官方死因是什么
What's the official cause of death?
还没有验尸
Autopsy hasn't been performed yet.
急救人员把他送去了总医院
EMTs brought him to general,
但是我要求他们把他送回 我们的停尸房方便尸检
But I requested they ship him back To our morgue for the postmortem.
很好
Good.
嘿  醒醒
Hon. Wake up.
你穿着衣服干嘛
Why are you dressed?
你还没睡
You haven't sleep?
我想去告诉谢丽尔  唐尼的死讯
I want to go tell Cheryl that Donny died.
现在是凌晨四点
It's 4:00 in the morning.
路上要花两个小时
They're nearly two hours away.
我到那的时候她就该起来了
I figure by the time I get there, she'll be awake.
亲爱的  回到床上来
Babe, come back to bed.
过会打电话给她
Call her in a few hours.
这种事要当面说
It's the sort of thing she needs to hear face-to-face.
你没事吧
Is everything okay?
没事
Everything's fine.
怎么了
Why?
上周我明白你因为迪巴拉的听证会
Last week, I understood that you were stressed out
精疲力尽  我给你留出平静的空间
About the Dibala "m" and "m," and I gave you your space.
但是那都过去了 但你还是这样
But that's over now, and you're still acting...
我很担心你
I'm worried about you.
别这样
Don't be.
我没事
I'm fine.
真的
Really.
如果有什么不对劲  你一定要告诉我
And you'd tell me if you weren't?
保证
Promise?
我保证
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
唐尼·康普森  三十九岁
Donny Compson, age 39.
我们能直奔主题吗
Can we cut to the money shot?
问题在心脏  所以我们看看他的心脏
It's his heart, so let's look at his heart.
漂亮的Y形切口
Nice y-incision.
没有行医执照不能尸检
You can't perform an autopsy without a medical license.
真的吗
Really?
我认为我已经搞砸了
'Cause I don't think there's anything I could screw up
所有事了
That we haven't already screwed up.
开胸尸检
Opening postmortem incision.
从胸骨中线开始
Beginning at the midline of the sternum.
很奇怪
That's odd.
这看上去像
It almost looks like he's...
他在流血
Bleeding.
我觉得尸检有必要停一下
I think the autopsy's gonna have to wait a little bit.
他短暂恢复知觉
He was briefly conscious,
然后收缩压下降到60
Then his systolic dipped below 60,
然后又昏过去了
And he was out again.
关于复活的鉴别诊断
Differential diagnosis for resurrection.
-开始  -很明显他没死
- Go.  - Obviously he wasn't dead.
他的心跳低到了急救员观察不到的速率
His heart slowed enough that the EMTs--
他没死证明我们所做的完全没有错
Yes, the fact that he's not dead means we did absolutely nothing wrong.
有几个案例证明
There's several documented cases
河豚毒素摄入会导致假死
Where tetrodotoxin ingestion caused apparent death.
不是食物的问题  而是自身上有的
It wasn't something he ate. It's something he already had.
他的父亲
And his dad,
-祖父还有  -心跳缓慢
- And his grandpa, and...  - Extreme bradycardia
可能导致病态窦房结综合征
Could be caused by sick sinus syndrome.
-窦房阻塞  -如果问题不在心脏呢
- Sinoatrial block.  - What if it's not his heart?
让我们从无关紧要的假设开始
Let's work from the tenuous assumption
如果我们不是那群花了几天时间
That we're not idiots
仔细检查他心脏的笨蛋
Who've spent days examining a heart
并且继续错下去 在他心脏罢工前几小时
Up, down, sideways-- Declaring it healthy just a few hours
还宣布它的健康
Before it basically shut down.
那么我们要考虑一些过去没注意到的地方
So we need to think about causes in places you didn't look.
可能是新陈代谢的问题
Could be metabolic.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
是不是遗传性 自身免疫病
What about a genetic predisposition To an autoimmune disease?
相关抗体
Isolated anti-ro antibody
可能导致完全性心脏阻滞
Could cause complete heart block.
而且可以遗传四代
Could also be passed through four generations.
自体免疫症
Autoimmune it is.
给他用类固醇
Start him on steroids.
感觉怎么样了
Hey. How you feeling?
头疼的要命
My whole head is killing me.
你刚从重度昏迷中醒过来
You just came through a severe trauma.
你记得什么么吗
What do you remember?
我正在把我的衣服放到干衣机里
I was changing my laundry over to the dryer.
没有别的吗
That's it?
你被宣布死亡了
You were declared dead.
你都被送去尸检了
You made it all the way to autopsy.
我的下巴很疼
My jaw aches.
而且我没有奥尔托利综合症
And obviously I don't have Ortoli syndrome.
从鬼门关被拉回来 没什么可兴奋的
It's hard to get too excited about coming back from the dead
不管我怎么做  不管你给我什么
When anything I do, anything you give me--
结果都是一样的
It all ends the same way.
外耳和中耳反应正常
Outer and middle ear respond well.
听觉阈频率正常
Hearing thresholds are normal at all frequencies.
耳膜完全健康
Eardrum is perfectly healthy.
如果我
What if I, uh...
如果有时候我听到有人在窃窃私语呢
If I sometimes hear whispering?
那可能的确有人在窃窃私语
Then you're probably hearing someone whispering.
我小的时候在菲律宾 整过牙
I had some dental work done in the Philippines when I was a kid.
里面的金属填充物可能会腐蚀
Adjoining metal fillings could corrode
从而收听到调幅广播
And pick up a.m. Radio signals.
张嘴
Open your mouth.
你的填充物没问题
Your fillings don't touch.
所以没有理由能解释我听到那些声音
So there's no reason for me to be hearing things.
我只能说 你听觉健康
I can only tell you that you're hearing sounds as you should.
如果你也能听见不该听见的声音
If you're also hearing sounds that you shouldn't,
那就是精神问题
Well, that would be psychosis.
你只能跟脑科的人谈
You'd have to talk to someone who does brain.
我只负责耳科
I only do ears.
神人
Bravo!
一天内你完成了120个小时工作  真神奇
It's amazing how you did 120 hours in one day.
我状态不好
I wasn't on my best behavior.
我承认
I admit.
请允许我
Allow me.
从现在开始  我会监督由你指导的实践课
From now on, I'm gonna supervise your practicum requirements.
没这个必要了
That won't be necessary.
你想再惹怒另一个医生吗
You want to annoy another doctor first?
-最终  -真的没必要
- Eventually  - It's not necessary,
因为我还没准备好继续当医生
Because I'm not ready to be a doctor again.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你要在外面睡吗
Are you sleeping out here?
只是  看着电视就睡着了
Just...dozed off in front of the TV.
需要连床都铺上
With bedding?
也许
Maybe!
我不能睡里面
I can't sleep in there.
暖气糟透了
The heater's screwed up.
如果你需要找人聊聊
If you need to talk...
如果  如果你需要帮助
If--if you need more help--
我只是累了
I'm just tired.
我就在这里
I'm right here.
很好
Great.
你能"就在"别的地方吗
Can you be right here somewhere else?
我下巴还是痛
My jaw still hurts.
我牙齿  真的  非常地痛
My tooth-- Actually, a lot.
很抱歉  你的止痛药用量已经达到上限了
I'm sorry, you're maxed out on your pain meds.
睡一觉吧
Try to sleep.
牙医检查了被这个人拔出的牙齿
Dentist looked at the tooth the guy pulled out.
没有发现什么问题
There was nothing wrong with it.
那除了发现他是个傻子以外
So aside from him being an idiot,
我们还有什么发现
What else have we learned?
疼痛是真实的  肯定来自于身体的某个部位
The pain is real. It's coming from somewhere.
会不会是骨癌
What about bone cancer?
你没法把骨癌和心脏问题联系起来
You can't connect bone cancer to the heart.
豪斯觉得可以这件事等到早上再解决
House figure this can wait till the morning?
事实上  他告诉卡迪他还没有准备好来工作
Actually, he told Cuddy he's not ready to work.
他辞职了
He quit?
-很显然  -这不过是豪斯的高压攻势
- Apparently. - It's a power play.
他明天就会回来了
He'll be back tomorrow.
骨癌可以引发副肿瘤综合症
Bone cancer could trigger a paraneoplastic syndrome,
导致心房关闭
Which shuts down the heart.
原发性骨癌是非遗传性的
Primary bone cancer isn't hereditary.
李弗劳明综合征
Li-fraumeni syndrome.
它是遗传的  而且会增加
It's hereditary, and it increases
得骨癌的可能性
A person's risk of having bone cancer.
你有别的理论吗
You have another theory?
我的理论是这不是骨癌
My theory is it's not bone cancer.
伽玛测量能确定肿瘤的所在地
Gamma survey would locate the tumors.
我今天喝了浓豌豆汤
I had pea soup today.
你现在肯定会喜欢上我的气息
You'd love my breath right now.
我今天晚上没能跑步
I didn't get a chance to run tonight.
豪斯他  他出了点问题
House is... Is having issues.
我今天很想你
I missed you a lot today.
我最想做的就是
All I want to do is...
你知道的
You know.
外侧楔骨没有发现癌
No cancers on the lateral cuneiform bone.
舟骨也没有发现异样
Navicular's also clean.
奇斯对我撒谎了
Chase is lying to me.
我知道你清楚真相
And I know you know.
告诉我到底怎么回事  求你了
Tell me what's going on, please.
我只能把跟他讲的再跟你说一遍
I'm gonna tell you the same thing I told him...
去跟你的配偶谈谈
Talk to your spouse.
不吃早饭吗
No breakfast?
今天不吃
Not today.
我产生幻觉了
I'm hallucinating.
发生了什么事
What happened?
这次不是视觉上的
It's nothing visual this time.
我能听见有人在窃窃私语
I hear whispering.
这就是你奇怪举止的原因
Is that why you've been acting so weird?
-也是你辞职的原因吗  -我在变严重
- Is that why you quit? - I'm losing it.
我相信肯定会有个合理解释的
I'm sure there's a rational explanation.
是不是风声
The wind?
-或者是邻居家的电视  -我都检查过了
- A neighbor's TV?  - I checked everything.
真正可怕的是我在不服用维科丁的情况下
What's really scary is that I hear whispering
还能听见有人在耳语
While not on vicodin.
我要重返梅菲尔德好好检查下自己
I'm gonna check myself back into Mayfield.
好吧
Okay.
你说好吧
Okay?
你不觉得会有一个更合理的解释吗
You don't think there might be a logical explanation?
我漏掉的
Something I missed?
你是我认识的最聪明的人
You're the smartest guy I know.
如果你都没弄明白  那就根本不存在
If you haven't thought of it, it doesn't exist.
我会开车送你去
I'll drive you over.
不过我要先泡杯茶
I just need to make some tea first.
你知道的
You know.
知道你是个混蛋吗  没错
That you're an ass? Yeah.
你偷听我和过世的女友讲话
You overheard me talking to my dead girlfriend
还自我陶醉说
And thought to yourself, "hmm...
"我该怎么从中获得乐趣呢"
What kind of fun can I have with this?"
你干嘛要跟她讲话
Why are you talking to her?
你身边的大活人都失踪了
You run out of living people?
你可以跟我讲  我就在这
You can talk to me. I'm right here.
我想她
I miss her.
跟她说话能让我感觉好点
Talking to her makes me feel better.
和你讲就不会
You don't.
病人罗兰·梅鲍姆  27岁
Patient Lauren Maybaum, 27,
两天前因严重腹痛住院
Presented two days ago with severe abdominal pain.
对不起  我来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
昨天你说你还没准备好回来工作
Yesterday you said you weren't ready.
昨天我确实没有
Yesterday I wasn't.
-今天我准备好了  -那明天呢
- Today I am.  - And tomorrow
有没有可能给我五天预报好早些知道
Is it possible for me to get a five-day forecast?
我感觉好多了  很感谢你不那么关心
I'm feeling much better. Thank you for not asking.
要么你确实出现了问题
Either you did have a problem--
我不能忽视
Which I can't ignore.
要么你在耍我
Or you were jerking me around--
我还是不能忽视 你是个女人
Which I can't ignore. You are a woman.
你可以做任何事情
You can do anything.
比如说  我能让你去外面和我谈
For example, I can talk to you outside.
你确定你只是一个女人吗
Are you sure you're only one woman?
这是一个你扮演雇员 我扮演老板的地方
This is the part where You play the employee, and I play the boss.
我能看见你的乳头  该你了
I can see your nipples. Your turn.
-这些孩子在  -难怪她那么讨厌他
- These kids are...  - No wonder she hates him.
这不是厌恶
Mm, that's not hate.
-这是前戏  -这是不合适的
- It's foreplay. - It's inappropriate.
伽玛测量显示没有肿瘤
Gamma survey revealed no tumors.
所以就不是骨癌了
So it's not bone cancer.
奇斯在哪
Where's Chase?
不知道
Don't know.
两个谜团  有意思
Two mysteries, cool.
有什么想法吗
Theories?
我是不是进来早了
Did I come in too soon?
好吧  我再出去转一圈
Okay, I'm gonna take another lap.
等我回来的时候我要听到三个新点子
And I want three new ideas by the time I come back.
得有一个不蠢的
One of them's got to be not stupid.
有痛感的地方  就有神经
Where there's pain... There's nerves.
自发性遗传感受神经病   第一类
Hereditary sensory autonomic neuropathy, type one.
脑干中的信息传达
Miscommunication in the brain stem
把神经痛错判为牙痛
Mistakes nerve pain for tooth pain.
这也能解释心动过缓
It would explain the bradycardia too.
我想加上"遗传性"这个词
And I like the word "hereditary" in the title.
立痛定[镇痛药]可以治好他
Carbamazepine fixes him.
我马上去准备药
I'll get him started on the medication.
不需要  奇斯特别问过他能不能由他处理
Nope, Chase specifically asked if he could do it.
在家里睡大觉
Sleep at home.
这样我就不用做伽玛测量了
So I didn't do the gamma survey.
-是不是骨癌  -不是
- Is it bone cancer?  - No.
你得感谢我没有浪费你的时间
You should congratulate me for not wasting your time.
你想不想得到帮助
Are you getting some help?
或者说从现在起你就随遇而安了
Or is this the way things are gonna be from now on?
可悲的是你还没得到帮助
What's pathetic is you haven't gotten help
因为你想让自己不舒服
Because you want to feel bad.
你想变得痛苦
You want to suffer,
因为如果你内疚  就自认为不是个神经病
'Cause if you feel guilty, then you're not a psychopath.
病人需要立痛定
Patient needs some carbamazepine.
我不管那个房间有多吓人
Now, I don't care how much that room scares you,
你得去工作
You're doing your job.
离你从单子上划掉这个可能性 还要多长时间
How long before you cross This one off the list?
几个小时
A couple of hours.
你朝别人开过枪吗
You ever shoot anyone?
开过两次
Twice.
你杀过人吗
You ever kill anyone?
没有
No.
我倒是知道有人做过
I know a few guys who did, though.
他们能心安吗
Did they ever get over it?
我认识的一个上尉把这个比喻成清除垃圾
A captain I know compares it to taking out the trash,
根本不当一回事
Like it's nothing.
可是我之前有个拍档
Other hand, I got an ex-partner
把自己灌得烂醉如泥
Who nearly drank himself into oblivion.
他有寻求帮助吗
Did he get help?
有的
Yeah.
可是没有用
Help didn't help.
噢  天啊
Oh, god!
怎么了
What is it?
我失禁了
I went to the bathroom.
病人失禁
Patient's lost bowel control.
证明不是遗传性感觉自主神经病变
Means we were wrong about h-san,
并且他的病情在恶化
And it means he's getting worse fast.
没人想做他的
Wouldn't want to be the duty nurse
值班护士  明白吗
Assigned to his floor. Get it?
大便护士
"Doody" nurse?
好吧  回到医学上来
Fine. Do the doctor thing.
自体免疫絮乱可以解释
An autoimmune disorder could explain--
我们给他用过类固醇  他没有反应
We put him on steroids. He didn't respond.
不是自体免疫的问题  可能是肝豆状核变性
It's not autoimmune. Could be Wilson's disease.
这个病事先就会对肝脏造成影响
A disease that advanced would've hit the liver.
可能是肝脏已经出现异常
It is possible the liver's so far gone,
化验数据没有体现出来
The labs look normal.
值得一试
It's worth a shot.
给他用青霉胺
Go treat with penicillamine.
如果没有好转  马上回来
And when he doesn't get better, come back quickly,
好让我们讨论其他治疗方法
So we can get one more shot at it.
求主宽恕  我有罪
Bless me, father, for I have sinned.
请慢慢道来
Take your time.
你多久没来忏悔了
How long has it been since your last confession?
我杀了人
I killed a man.
可是我是对的
But it was the right thing to do.
他人的生死权不是掌握在你手里
Who lives or dies is not your decision to make.
但在手术室里就是这样的
Sometimes in the operating room it feels like it.
我是个医生
I'm a doctor.
那样你应该比任何人都清楚
Well, then you should know more than anybody
每个生命都是神圣的
That every human life is sacred.
为什么
Why?
告诉我  一个杀害千百人命的独裁者
Tell me what's sacred about a dictator
他的生命能有多神圣
That kills hundreds of thousands of his own people.
那一个杀死他病人的医生又能有多神圣呢
What is sacred about a doctor who kills a patient?
你担心宽恕我是错误的吗
Is it just the slippery slope you're worried about?
害怕宽恕一个杀了坏人的我
Afraid that forgiving me
哪怕杀的是世界上最坏的人  一个独裁者
For killing the worst people on earth such a bad president?
我保证
I promise...
我不会告诉任何人
I won't tell anyone.
请宽恕我吧
Just forgive me.
我为你欢呼10次也减轻不了你的罪
Saying ten hail isn't going to do you any good.
那我能做什么
Then what do I have to do?
上帝要我做什么
What does god need me to do?
你不能得到赦免
You can't have absolution
直到你承担你的责任
Without first taking responsibility.
你需要向警方自首
You have to turn yourself into the police.
什么
What...
然后在监狱里度过余生吗
And go to jail for the rest of my life?
公理何在
What's just about that?
我做的是对的
I did the right thing.
一定有别的方法
There has to be another way.
你想得到赦免  我已经告诉你怎么做了
You want absolution, I've told you how to get it.
把这个寄到州执照委员会
Send this in to the state licensing board.
我已经给你签字了
I've signed off on all your hours.
为什么
Why?
因为这是比较容易的解决方法
Because it's easier this way.
你对我不爽
You're uncomfortable with me.
我没有
No.
没必要照章办事
Going by the book was pointless.
你从中得不到任何长进
You were gonna learn nothing.
好  我还以为是因为性紧张
Good, I thought it was because of the sexual tension.
不是什么性紧张
There was no sexual tension.
是紧张
There was tension.
而且  它让我觉得妙趣横生
And...it made me feel funny, so...
给
Here.
太糟了
That's too bad.
我刚开始喜欢 做这种热血老师
I was kind of getting into the whole Hot-for-teacher thing.
你确定你没事吗
You sure you're okay?
是的  错误警报
Yeah. False alarm.
我们呢
What about us?
像这样
We're good...
就很好了
Just like this.
你按我的按钮  我按你的[互相帮忙]
You press my buttons, I press yours.
你说的按钮是指
By buttons, you mean...
你的确让我妙趣横生
You do make me feel funny.
你不会死的
You're not gonna die.
我已经接受这个事实了
I've accepted it.
没事
It's okay.
除了高足弓
In addition to high arches
还有一些吞拿鱼形的玻璃碗
And some crystal bowl in the shape of a tuna,
你还遗传了一个定时炸弹按钮
You also inherited a self-destruct button.
它在脑干上形成
It forms in the brain stem.
准确的讲  它是个动脉瘤
Technically, it's an aneurysm.
受神经压迫控制
Presses on the nerves,
控制着牙痛和心率
That control everything from tooth pain to heart rate.
它随着你的年龄长大
As you get older, it gets bigger,
直到最后
Until finally...
那按钮
The button...
称为囊性颅内动脉瘤
Which I'll call intracranial berry aneurysm,
那是我一个高中朋友的花名
'Cause I had a friend in high school with that name--
它截停从你的脑到心脏的信号
Stops the signal from your brain to your heart.
然后砰
And bam!
我怎么知道你不是骗我
How do I know you're not still lying to me?
说我很健康只是为了让我好受点
Saying I'm healthy just to make me feel better?
听起来确实是那样的
It does sound that way, doesn't it?
可是这次  不是安慰剂
But this time, no sugar pills.
我将会切进你的脑 让你觉得我在医治它
I'm gonna cut into your brain To make you think that I'm fixing it.
而且如果我们的假试验得到确认
And if our fake tests confirm it,
我还会给你儿子动手术
I'm gonna be cutting into your son's brain too,
因为我认定是这样的
'Cause I'm just that committed.
迈克尔会没事吗
Michael's gonna be okay?
除非他从这里出去的时候被车撞死
Unless he walks out of here and gets run over by a bus,
那样的话  我会重新考虑你的因果论
In which case, I will reconsider your fate argument.
你想打个电话给他吗
You want to give him a call?
我的病人是没有探病时间的
Visiting hours don't apply to my patients.
是的
Yeah...
等下就打
In a bit.
好的
Yeah.
我就说嘛
That's what I thought.
"让孩子避免伤痛"这种说法太恶心了
The "saving the kid from pain" stuff was crap.
你不过是想让你生命中的任何事
You just don't want anything in your life
无论何时何地都
That won't let you do whatever the hell you want to do
不能阻挡你的脚步而已
Whenever the hell you want to do it.
这些你曾经可以信手拈来
You've had it easy.
抱歉让你死了一趟
Sorry to screw you up.
妈妈
Mom?
也许我们出院的时候
Maybe when we get out of here...
你喜欢什么电影
What kind of movies you like?
他失踪八个小时了
He's been missing for eight hours.
罗伯特·奇斯
Robert Chase.
C-h-a-s-e
C-h-a-s-e.
没事了  他刚回来  抱歉
Never mind, he just walked in, sorry.
你应该打个电话给我
You could've called me.
我忘了
Oh, I-I've forgot.
忘了打电话给我  现在已经凌晨两点了
To call me? It's 2:00 in the morning.
你去了哪里
Where were you?
还喝醉了
Ooh, you're drunk.
好吧  我
All right, I...
我需要颓废一下  我需要
I needed to get wasted. I did.
所以现在感觉好点了
And now I'm better.
你在瞒着我什么
What aren't you telling me?
什么也没有
Nothing.
爸爸
Hi, dad.
我过去
I have been
纠结于一些错误
Focusing on the wrong thing
忽略了美好的日子
And those were good times
威尔森
Wilson
你这个笨蛋
You're just stupid
看到了吗 他的确好多了
You see he really is getting better